<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gender Neutral Austin</title>
    <description>We deserve to pee in peace.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:02:25 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:02:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kismet Cafe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/HITWaustin/&quot;&gt;Kismet&lt;/a&gt; has some really yummy Greek &amp;amp; Middle Eastern food, along with amazing veggie options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also have two single-stall gendered restrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to an employee at the end of last month, who was already aware of the issue. They took down my contact information, but informed me that the owner would be leaving town in a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t heard back from them, but will check in again in a couple of weeks. Switching signs isn’t time consuming, but I realize it takes a while to research the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 10:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/kismet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/kismet/</guid>
        
        
        <category>restaurant</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Varsity Pizza &amp; Pints</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/thevarsitypizzapints/&quot;&gt;Varsity&lt;/a&gt; serves pizza and beer, along with having sportsball games on large screens in case your friends aren’t boring enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also host weekly Super Smash Bros Melee (SSBM) tournaments - my reason for frequenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost three months ago, I contacted them on Facebook, informing them that their “women’s” restroom is single-stall and should therefore be gender-neutral. My messages were read, but ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After fruitlessly asking employees and managers - week after week - for the best way to get in contact with the owner, he happened to be there one evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spoke for some time, which revealed quite a bit of stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He ignored my messages because he didn’t think it applied to his establishment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He was personally offended that these issues were being brought up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He believes trans women should not use the “women’s” restroom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He would look into the issue, and get back to me if he had any questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear: there are two restrooms at Varsity. The “men’s” restroom is not single-stall - there is a wall between the toilet and urinal so that somehow counts. I told him that the best option is to make both restrooms gender-neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overwhelming majority of people who show up for SSBM tournaments (usually, myself being the exception) are cis males. I realize that these are not the only people visiting the establishment, but the gender break-down is consistent or similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have noticed some of my fellew Smashers have started using the “women’s” restroom if the other is occupied. To nobody’s surprise, there has been zero problems with this, and has more than likely gone unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to keep going there, and maybe one day I’ll hear some good news.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/varsity/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/varsity/</guid>
        
        
        <category>bar</category>
        
        <category>restaurant</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mage's Sanctum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/MagesSanctum/&quot;&gt;Mage’s Sancum&lt;/a&gt; is a really nifty shop in South Austin for all of your table-top gaming needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had two single-stall restrooms that were gendered. I talked to them, and they ended up switching the signs out the next day, making them gender-neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was first establishment that made the change after I talked to them, so it really motivated me to try it out on other places and document the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody here has been more than pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 07:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mages-sanctum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/mages-sanctum/</guid>
        
        
        <category>gaming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wheatsville</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/spiderhousecafe/&quot;&gt;Wheatsville&lt;/a&gt; on Guadalupe has two gendered restrooms, but you can go pee comfortably while waiting for your Popcorn Tofu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You don’t have any gender neutral restrooms. What is your policy on what restrooms people may use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wheatsville:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hi, thanks for asking. While not a policy per se, we encourage people to self-identify and use the bathroom that feels the most comfortable. We don’t have any single room restrooms in either store but do offer private stalls in both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve encountered no problems whatsoever here, although:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cashiers do tend to use gendered greetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 02:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wheatsville/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wheatsville/</guid>
        
        
        <category>cafe</category>
        
        <category>bar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spider House</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are no gender-neutral restrooms at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/spiderhousecafe/&quot;&gt;Spider House&lt;/a&gt;, both on the cafe side and ballroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, people can use whatever restroom they want, according to this conversation with Spider House on Facebook:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is your policy on what restrooms people may use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spider House:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We don’t have an official policy, but it’s basically that we have all types of customers- straight, gay, trans, etc. they may use any bathroom they choose. It’s never been an issue as Spider House is very welcoming to all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is your turf, no matter how you identify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I frequent Spider House, and I’ve never been told anything about using whatever restroom I want, there are some criticisms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers might give you looks, walk out of the restroom to check the sign on the door, or leave&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who work there tend to use gendered language to customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 07:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/spider-house/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/spider-house/</guid>
        
        
        <category>cafe</category>
        
        <category>bar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Daito</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/daito2015/&quot;&gt;Daito&lt;/a&gt; is a Japanese restaurant on Guadalupe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went there, they had two gendered single-stall restrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days after talking with Management, they informed me that new signs have been purchased for their restrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really neat knowing that a few minutes of conversation with people really does make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 09:15:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/daito/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/daito/</guid>
        
        
        <category>restaurant</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pinballz Arcade</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/PinballzArcade/&quot;&gt;Pinballz&lt;/a&gt; on Research only has two gendered restrooms, but don’t let that stop you from choosing whichever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook Conversation with Pinballz:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is your policy on what restrooms people may use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spider House:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Guests can use the restroom they are most comfortable with at our locations. The new location, Lake Creek, will have a family bathroom anyone can use by requesting a key, if someone wants another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t get in any sort of trouble for using one of their restrooms, but:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are children there sometimes and parents may give you looks in the restrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pinballz-arcade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pinballz-arcade/</guid>
        
        
        <category>arcade</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
